Alexandra Hernandez

San Diego, California 92122 (951) 595-9228

alexavndrarh@gmail.com, arh003@ucsd.edu Portfolio LinkedIn GitHub

UC San Diego undergraduate majoring in Cognitive Sciences and minoring in Computer Sciences. Specializing in machine learning, programming, APIs, algorithm development, data analysis, frontend and backend development, and application testing.

EXPERIENCE

Scripps Institute of Oceanography

Data Management Assistant

La Jolla, CA

Aug 2023-Present

Processing raw data from researchers using Excel and CSV files, and running existing programs to reconfigure the data to be understandable. Responsible for documenting datasets with appropriate metadata and uploading data to existing databases and online repositories. Maintaining publicly submitted data available via locally-developed, web-based and making minor updates to project websites.

Qualcomm Institute UC San Diego

WordPress Developer

La Jolla, CA

Sept 2022-Aug 2023

Website structuring and maintenance for Qualcomm Institute's TREDS. Using LMS applications, Google Cloud API, HTML, and CSS, as well as WordPress and PHP. Implemented digital programs, collect and analyze data and research for supervisors. Work with SEO concept and tools for main website. Manage and develop software integrations.

WalkMe UC San Diego

La Jolla, CA

Data Analyst

May 2022–Sept 2022

Worked on frontend development, data analytics, and implementation for WalkMe program at UC San Diego. Implementing for university websites and programs with prototyping/testing using dataset information. Used JIRA and HTTPS for managing software. Utilized automation with content via WalkMe and DAP.

EDUCATION

University of California, San Diego

La Jolla, CA

Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Sciences—Machine Learning & Neural Computation. Minoring in Computer Science.

Sept 2021-Present

GPA: 3.6

Honors: Marshall College Provost Honors (FA21, WI22, SP22, FA22).

Involvement: Cognitive Sciences Department WI23 (COGS 1: Introduction to Cognitive Sciences Instructional

Assistant), Associated Students (2021-2023)

SKILLS

Java, Python, JSON, MATLAB and Git/GitHub/GitLab; VSCode, Jupyter, and DataSpell. User of Terminal environments and program testing. SQL, Google Cloud API, and HTTPS/XML knowledge. Experience of JIRA (IBM Toolchain Build Tool) and basic Kubernetes knowledge. Worked with SDLC and software and source code maintenance.

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and Content Management Systems. Worked with user feedback and pair programming. Experience with Google Sheets and Docs, Microsoft Excel and Word.

PROJECTS

Digital Art Keywords: Data science research project analyzing the relationship between keywords and DeviantArt content with Python via DeviantArt API, NumPy, Seaborn, MatPlotLib, and SciPy. Group project via Git workflow/Jupyter Notebooks.

Astrologify: Console app that uses Spotify API, Python, and Git to create user playlist with given user data. Used VSCode and GitHub.

Reminder App: Desktop program that uses EasyApp UI and Java to create reminders for the user through tasks and lists; incorporates times and dates. Created using NetBeans IDE.